One year,
I had the hallway renovated.
I hired a relative to take the job.
Turns out there were quality issues.
One resident slipped
on the stairs at night and died.
I figured
I should fix it before it got worse,
so I redid the hallway.
But I had no money left.
So I secretly
took materials from maintenance
and got some supplies.
I set up a small shack
in the parking garage
and stashed the materials there.
Officer Ran,
why did you go to the garage?
I just thought, once I had enough,
I'd fix it properly.
You tell me, why'd he get so much cement?
This cement must be about 100 kilos.
But then,
that year,
Ju… July…
Rats. I love catching rats.
Xiaohe, slow down.
Xiaohe.
Uncle Ran, this underground maze
is so cool!
Xiaohe,
stay close to me.
What if a rat suddenly jumps out?
How would I know
there was a head and two arms
in that tool bag?
I did think about calling the police.
Did you?
-Who is it?
-Qian Dajun.
You brat!
Dad.
Who are you calling Dad?
When are you going to sell
the place in Yuanlongli?
Soon.
-Soon.
-Not a chance.
I've heard about it!
They say that place eats people.
No one dares live there.
Prices are dropping like crazy.
Back then,
rumors were going around
that the place was killing people.
If I'd called the police,
neither my place nor my relatives'
would've sold.
After thinking it through,
I decided to keep it quiet.
I figured I'd find a safer place,
hide it first,
then deal with it when I got the chance.
Careful, Xiaohe.
I put it in the chicken coop.
I was afraid my uncle would find it.
So I thought
I should move it to a safer place.
But that drain inlet was too small.
No matter what, it wouldn't fit.
So I had to move it again.
When I came back,
I found the head was gone.
I couldn't find it anywhere.
So I took the bag
and buried it
in the woods behind the complex.
I was terrified for a long time,
having nightmares every day.
I went on like that for five years.
I thought it was over,
but then,
in the summer of 2002,
my uncle, Ge Jingsong,
pulled the head out.
Murder!
Officer Ran went like a man possessed,
tearing through the whole complex,
searching everywhere.
DANGER, ELECTRICITY
I was guilty and scared,
so I dug the bag back up
and moved it.
SO I MOVED THE BAG
But later, I almost got caught
by Officer Ran.
Open it.
At that time,
the underground garage
was under construction.
I took advantage of the moment
and stuffed the arm bones into the cement
and made a cement block.
I thought this time, no one would find it.
But I didn't expect,
after more than ten years,
I'd be the one to dig it up myself.
These bones have been
weighing on me ever since.
I hate Yuanlongli!
I hate it so much!
I wish it were torn down sooner!
Just tear it down!
And these bones
and all the monsters all gone!
Gone for good!
Then no one would care
about this case anymore!
Never again.
FAIR AND JUST, LOYAL AND TRUE
What Qian Dajun said is mostly reliable.
What he mentioned, the 1997 garage
and the rooftop incident,
I did go through
those things with Uncle Ran.
Preliminarily, it looks like Qian Dajun
has nothing to do with Xu Meng
and her father's deaths.
Qian Dajun's arrest
means Yuanlongli
probably won't be demolished early.
We still have time to keep investigating.
Oh, and we should
circle back to Qian Dajun,
question him again about
everything related to the June 30th case.
Maybe it'll lead to something bigger.
Okay.
Uncle He.
Uncle He. Good afternoon.
I was just appointed by the company
as the Yuanlongli project's
head of redevelopment.
JIN MANLANG, RELOCATION MANAGER
The company also promised
that if the demolition wraps up quickly,
I'll be promoted to vice president.
-So…
-So, what's that got to do with me?
Uncle He,
I'm not like Qian Dajun, I'm different.
I believe in sincerity
and peace above all.
Uncle He, this place,
I'm not renting this place anymore.
The rent will be returned double.
Please move out.
Double the rent.
Wait.
It's in black and white.
It's legal and valid.
I paid, so I have the right to stay
for three full months.
If you don't like it,
you can go to court and sue me.
How long it takes, I don't care.
Uncle He, let's talk this over.
I'll pay you triple rent.
Wang Laosan, come here.
Get out of here.
I've worked myself
to the bone all these years
and finally got my chance
to turn things around.
Now, anyone who gets in my way,
don't blame me, Jin Manlang,
for turning ruthless!
Who was it that said "peace above all"?
-Uncle He.
-See yourself out.
Well…
Wolf, don't get mad.
Peace above all.
Darn it!
Wolf. Wolf!
What's that?
-That bag looks heavy.
-Did you see that?
-That bag must be money.
-Powering on.
Good news! Good news!
The company has benefits for everyone!
100k yuan per household,
extra compensation.
Just sign the contract.
-Take the money now!
-Let's go!
-Go take a look. Check it out.
-Take the money now!
-Limited spots.
-Me first.
-First come, first served!
-Me first!
Is it real?
-They're really paying!
-Is it real?
Come on! Line up!
Line up, line up!
Benefits for everyone!
Don't rush!
One at a time! Don't rush!
One at a time!
Meng, you've got to hold on,
stay and keep me company.
Don't let a little money blind you.
OFFICER HE, MENG'S BEEN DETAINED!
Let Mr. Meng enjoy this
Western symphony!
So we're talking it out now?
No more fighting?
Why are you all staring at me?
Keep the music going.
Play something upbeat.
Can't you see the door's open?
Hurry up.
Get Mr. Meng out here.
STAGED SCENE. DO NOT IMITATE
I'll send you all to hell!
What are you doing?
You old fool, want to die?
You brat!
I'll send you all to hell!
That's illegal! You hear me?
Call the police!
Call the police now!
I'll send you all to hell!
Come on!
Wolfie, you just won't go away.
Uncle He.
Qiao, what are you doing here?
Come in, come in.
Well, what do you want to drink?
I'll get it.
Uncle He, don't bother.
What's wrong?
I…
I didn't get our boss's approval,
but I had finance sign off
on a 50k moving fee for you.
Qiao, what's going on?
Didn't we agree
to fulfill Ran's wish together?
I know.
I appreciate it, but I'm not moving.
No matter the offer,
no matter the money, I won't move.
That's final! You should go.
Uncle He. Uncle He.
Our boss has reported you to the station.
You should be ready.
FORENSIC REPORT
Xia, Xia…
Xiaohe, go to Captain Zhao's office.
What's going on?
Captain Zhao, we're a private company.
It's not easy.
This project can't be delayed anymore.
If He Yuanhang keeps this up,
it won't just hurt
our company's legal rights,
it'll also undermine
what the residents deserve.
Your criminal department
needs to stand up for people like us!
I understand.
We will figure this out quickly
and give you answers. Alright?
Thank you, Captain Zhao.
Please hurry. This can't wait.
Come on. I'll walk you out.
Okay, okay.
-I'll head out then.
-Okay.
Captain Zhao, stand up for us!
-Alright.
-Okay. Take care.
What's with He Yuanhang?
Has he lost it again?
Captain Zhao, Captain Qu,
since you're both here,
I'd like to request
reopening the investigation
into the June 30th case.
June 30th?
That's ancient history.
He Xiaohe, you're just as crazy
as your dad.
Isn't this mess enough?
Captain Zhao,
before Captain Ran passed,
he secretly reopened the June 30th case.
These days, my dad and I
have been retracing his investigation.
Now we have solid leads
proving Wu Shanlong was framed.
The real killer is someone else.
Any suspects?
We are still checking.
Not yet.
Captain Zhao,
this whole thing started because my dad
found an unsent message
on Uncle Ran's old phone.
DRAFT, UNSENT MESSAGE
SAVED: 2003-01-31 13:09:37 TO: SIR
RAN: SIR, THE JUNE 30TH CASE
WAS WRONG, ALL WRONG
This message was written
on the day he died.
Uncle Ran died with that regret.
With the leads and evidence we have,
is it enough to reopen the case?
I trust my dad.
Just give him more time,
he'll definitely find
key clues in Yuanlongli.
We have to move fast.
Otherwise, we won't have the authority
to stop the legal demolition.
Got it.
YUANLONGLI INTERNATIONAL GARDEN
Tenant of 609, listen up!
All residents of Yuanlongli
have moved out.
Now, you're the only one left.
Your landlord has already sold the place.
Please leave immediately.
Otherwise,
the demolition team
will remove you by force.
Remove you by force.
HONGYUN HUIHUANG (DAHUIHUANG)
JIN MANSHAN
Tenant of 609, listen up!
All residents of Yuanlongli
have moved out.
Now, you're the only one left.
Your landlord has already sold the place.
Please leave immediately.
Otherwise,
the demolition team
will remove you by force.
Remove you by force.
Sir.
Sir,
are you trying to use
the golden birdcage effect?
All the monsters
in Yuanlongli are still here.
As long as I keep digging,
the devil will slip up.
Right now, I'll be the golden cage
and lure the devil out.
Then, I'll capture everything.
Powering on.
He, I'm giving you ten more minutes.
After that,
don't blame me for doing my job.
DAHUIHUANG
DAHUIHUANG NIGHTCLUB
How did Xu Zhihong die?
Where is Xu Meng?
Is she dead or alive?
DAHUIHUANG, JIN MANSHAN
Recognize this?
I really have no idea.
JIN MANSHAN
Pay up!
Since Wu became the factory director…
It shut down last month.
QINGSONG CEMENT FACTORY
DRAGON TIGER
When was the last time the father
and daughter were seen leaving home?
People said it was the day
before Hong Kong, China's handover.
Someone saw them leave,
-and they never came back.
-Never came back.
QINGSONG CEMENT FACTORY
Back in '97, someone came
to the video rental shop
to hire Wolfie to kill someone.
Pattia Club.
PATTIA CLUB
In the end, it was all to run away
from debt collectors.
PATTIA CLUB
ZHAO HONGMEI
Did she meet any clients
on her last day here?
I don't know.
ZHAO HONGMEI, ZHANG ERSONG, SONGBENTANG
A conflict is one thing,
but it wouldn't escalate
to the level of murder.
ZHANG ERSONG, SONGBENTANG
Su Yuzhi.
Are you saying Mr. Sun has something to do
with Mengmeng's disappearance?
SU YUZHI
Song Qingsong.
About that young woman
at the foot massage shop,
it's true I paid Wu Shanlong
to get rid of her.
Jin Manlang.
It's all chicken blood.
If it's human blood,
just shoot me on the spot.
JIN MANLANG, WAN QIMING
In the summer of 1996,
someone paid me 500 yuan
to spy on the unit opposite.
I have an alibi.
WAN QIMING, QIAN DAJUN
GOOD NEIGHBOR TAILOR SHOP, ALTERATIONS
QIAN DAJUN, YUANLONGLI ROOFTOP
The rooftop.
That cut was made after death,
likely during dismemberment.
High probability of homicide.
Qihuang Clinic.
QIHUANG CLINIC
Sun Zhengyong.
She took her dad and left.
They bought train tickets for July 1st.
QIHUANG CLINIC
YUANLONGLI UNDERGROUND GARAGE
Wu Shanlong said
he went and did the deed himself.
HU ANPING
Dajianchang.
Double Fish.
This dress is probably
worth more than this unit.
DAJIANCHANG, XU MENG'S HOME
MOUNT WU ACCIDENT
Is the accident investigation report
still available?
Yes. It's all still here.
Sir, your package.
This is the Mount Wu accident file.
We don't need it now.
MOUNT WU ACCIDENT
KIDDO
Kiddo, when we first moved here,
did you see a package
from Mount Wu, Kunhai?
I did.
At the time, it wasn't even opened,
I thought it was useless,
so I didn't take it.
Dad, is there a clue inside?
I just reviewed all info and leads
on the June 30th case,
and only the Mount Wu files
haven't been checked.
MOUNT WU ACCIDENT
Last minute!
Fifty-nine!
Fifty-eight!
-Fifty--
-Bro.
This is from me personally.
Th-This, Wolf, you really look out for us.
-Bro, H-He…
-He…
-He!
-It's him!
He.
Finally, changed your mind?
I'm telling you, stay away from my room!
Or I can still lock you up!
Got it, Officer He.
Darn it!
That old man's retired.
Why would I fear him?
Biao,
now you go seal off Room 609.
If you can't, I'll deal with you!
-Yes, sir.
-Mang, notify security,
lock down New York Block,
cordon it off!
Not even a fly gets in!
Got it, bro!
Captain Liu,
New York Block is cleared.
Now, take your team in and inspect.
Prepare the blast points!
AUGUST 24TH MOUNT WU ACCIDENT REPORT
LIST OF VICTIMS
XU ZHIHONG, XU MENG
Ran,
turns out I'm not the cage.
The cursed building is.
Officer.
Officer, where are you taking me?
Move. Move.
Qian Dajun.
Officer He.
FAIR AND JUST, LOYAL AND TRUE
Have you heard
of someone in Yuanlongli named
Yao Xincheng?
Yao Xincheng.
I know who that is.
YUANLONGLI INTERNATIONAL GARDEN
-Officer He! Officer He!
-You're not getting up there.
-Office He!
-Move!
It's sealed.
If you don't, I'll bite!
Officer He!
-Pay more!
You… What are you doing?
You're paying holdouts more?
What's that supposed to mean?
Just because we're not holdouts
doesn't mean we're pushovers!
Pay more, or I'll move back in!
You… What are you doing?
-Pay more!
DON'T LET HONEST PEOPLE LOSE OUT
EQUAL TREATMENT!
-Pay more!
You brat.
Everyone, calm down!
Don't get worked up!
I'll ask the company soon
to raise the compensation.
We don't want "soon", we want it now.
That's right!
Everyone, stay calm!
Stay calm!
Why are residents
rioting at the cursed building,
demanding huge compensation?
With over 20 years of history,
Yuanlongli, known as the cursed building,
is about to be demolished.
Let's witness together
the final chapter of this legendary place.
This cursed building will claim 18 lives.
Two more to go.
In there, isn't one still hiding?
-Pay more!
Where's He?
2002 YUANLONGLI OWNER/TENANT REGISTRY
-Hello?
-Hello? Who is this?
Hello.
I'm He Yuanhang,
a retired detective from Nanshan Branch.
I'd like to ask you something.
Hello, Officer He.
In 2002,
did you buy a place in Yuanlongli?
Yes.
But in 2003, I sold the place.
That's not right.
That place is still under your name.
Here's the thing.
The buyer signed the agreement, paid me,
and never came back
to transfer the ownership.
So the owner's name is still mine.
Right.
Over ten years ago,
a cop also came to me about this.
Was it the night
before New Year's Eve in 2003?
Yes, yes. The next day was New Year's Eve.
What was the buyer's name?
Yao Xincheng.
He had someone else handle it for him.
So this proxy and the one who sold you
the place in 2002
were the same person?
How did you know?
Pay more! Pay more!
NO SERVICE
He, I'm giving you my final warning!
Get out right now!
Otherwise, you face the consequences!
Biao, go turn the power all the way up.
-Pay more!
-What's going on?
-It's the sixth floor.
The one on the sixth floor.
STAGED SCENE. DO NOT IMITATE
Powering on.
This tune's kind of tacky.
-Tacky is what gives it power.
-Yea, power.
-Pay more!
Biao, Mang,
get that old fool down here now!
Stop!
Jin Manlang!
Stop this right now!
Why should I?
I've let that He guy
push me around for years.
Today, he's backing down.
I'm going upstairs now!
If you dare, I'll call the police!
Go ahead!
I DEMAND JUSTICE
DEMOLISH
HELL